Finding Aid for the Donald A. Glaser Papers, 1943-2013, bulk 1949-2003 GlaserDA
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Series 1 Biographical and Personal, 1910s-2016; 1
  - Subseries 9 Miscellaneous material, 1948-2016
    - Symphony patent IV, 2002; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_04 (Box C-1.10, Folder 4)
    - Symphony patent V, 2004; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_05 (Box C-1.10, Folder 5)
    - Symphony patent VI, 2004; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_06 (Box C-1.10, Folder 6)
    - "Tromba Marina" sheet music and recording, composed by John Thow, 2003; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_07 (Box C-1.10, Folder 7)
      Signed, printed booklets. Recording performed by the Lindsey Quartet
    - "Dr Glaser's Experiment" sheet music, composed by Darren Bloom, 2016; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_08 (Box C-1.10, Folder 8)
      Performed by the London Symphony Orchestra
    - Glaser Celebration, 2016 December; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_09 (Box C-1.10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 10 Oversize material, 1960-2003
    - Time-Life Nobel photo album, 1960; GlaserDA_01_10_11C_01; Photo album (Box C-1.11, Folder 1)
    - Catamaran drawings and photos, 1985-1987; GlaserDA_01_10_11C_02; Drawings and two photographs (Box C-1.11, Folder 2)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Fellow certificate, 2003; GlaserDA_01_10_11C_03 (Box C-1.11, Folder 3)
    - "Tromba Marina" original sheet music, composed by John Thow, 2003; GlaserDA_01_10_11C_04; Origingal handwritten sheet music, mounted on 11"x14" cardstock (Box C-1.11, Folder 4)
- Series 2 Education, 1943-2001; 2
  - Subseries 1 Case Institute of Technology, 1943-2001
    - Recital program, orchestra roster, fraternity roster, map, 1943-1944; GlaserDA_02_01_01C_01 (Box C-2.1, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: Bluebook I - Phys. Lab; Minerology, 1945; GlaserDA_02_01_01C_02 (Box C-2.1, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: Bluebook II - Mechanics, X-Rays; Acoustics, 1945; GlaserDA_02_01_01C_03 (Box C-2.1, Folder 3)
    - Notebook: Case School of Applied Science, ca. 1945-1949; GlaserDA_02_01_01C_04 (Box C-2.1, Folder 4)
      Last section is from Caltech
    - Case Institute alumni materials, 1960; 1981; 1991; 1994; 1995; 2001; GlaserDA_02_01_01C_05 (Box C-2.1, Folder 5)
    - Shankland Fund for Physics, 1982; GlaserDA_02_01_13B_34 (Box B-2.13, Folder 34)
  - Subseries 2 California Institute of Technology, 1946-1996
    Finished Ph.D. Fall 1949; received degree 1950
    - Notebook: Atomic Physics Ph 109 a,b; Spectroscopy Ph 107; Optics Ph 105 a, b; Quantum Mechanics Ph 113a, b; Quantum Mechanics (Summary of Schiff), undated; GlaserDA_02_02_02C_01 (Box C-2.2, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: Electricity and Magnetism Ph 101 abc, 1946-1947; GlaserDA_02_02_02C_02 (Box C-2.2, Folder 2)
    - Frosh Physics, Caltech, 1947-1949; GlaserDA_02_02_17B_06 (Box B-2.17, Folder 6)
    - Sophomore Physics, Caltech, 1947-1949; GlaserDA_02_02_17B_07 (Box B-2.17, Folder 7)
    - Notebook: Courses by Paul Epstein, 1948-1949; GlaserDA_02_02_03C_01 (Box C-2.3, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: Subject tabs, 1949; GlaserDA_02_02_03C_02 (Box C-2.3, Folder 2)
    - Thesis: The Momentum Distribution of Charged Cosmic Ray Particles Near Sea Level, 1950; GlaserDA_02_02_17B_08 (Box B-2.17, Folder 8)
    - Caltech Alumni Association - 59th Alumni Seminar Day Invitation, 1996 April 1; GlaserDA_02_02_03C_03 (Box C-2.3, Folder 3)
    - Caltech story on Glaser Trust, Techniques, 1996 May 20; GlaserDA_02_02_03C_04 (Box C-2.3, Folder 4)
- Series 3 University of Michigan, 1945-1960; 3
  - Subseries 1 Administrative material, 1945-1960
    - Teaching--policies, etcetera, 1945-1955; GlaserDA_03_01_05B_04 (Box B-3.5, Folder 4)
    - Teaching--policies, etcetera, 1945-1955; GlaserDA_03_01_05B_05 (Box B-3.5, Folder 5)
    - University data, 1950-1958; GlaserDA_03_01_05B_09 (Box B-3.5, Folder 9)
    - Fellowships, 1951-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_21 (Box B-3.2, Folder 21)
    - Graduate School, 1952; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_24 (Box B-3.2, Folder 24)
    - Michigan appointment data, 1952-1958; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_09 (Box B-3.3, Folder 9)
    - Academic procedure and administration, 1953-1957; GlaserDA_03_01_01B_01 (Box B-3.1, Folder 1)
    - Personnel, 1954-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_19 (Box B-3.3, Folder 19)
    - Personnel, 1954-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_20 (Box B-3.3, Folder 20)
    - Personnel, 1954-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_21 (Box B-3.3, Folder 21)
    - Office equipment, 1955; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_12 (Box B-3.3, Folder 12)
    - Doctoral committees, 1956; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_17 (Box B-3.2, Folder 17)
    - University procurement, 1956-1957; GlaserDA_03_01_05B_10 (Box B-3.5, Folder 10)
    - Engineering Research Institute procedure, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_19 (Box B-3.2, Folder 19)
    - Faculty, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_20 (Box B-3.2, Folder 20)
    - Statistical Research Laboratory, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_03_01_05B_02 (Box B-3.5, Folder 2)
    - Padua-Venice, 1957; GlaserDA_03_01_03B_16 (Box B-3.3, Folder 16)
    - Departmental, 1957-1960; GlaserDA_03_01_02B_16 (Box B-3.2, Folder 16)
      [1953-1960]
    - Merit increase correspondence, 1958 September-October; GlaserDA_03_01_01C_01 (Box C-3.1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2 Scientific projects and research, 1952-1960
    - Phoenix projects, 1952-1957; GlaserDA_03_02_04B_03 (Box B-3.4, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix projects, 1952-1957; GlaserDA_03_02_04B_04 (Box B-3.4, Folder 4)
    - Collection of papers on V particles and mesons, ca. 1953-1954; GlaserDA_03_02_01C_02 (Box C-3.1, Folder 2)
      Papers originally in Springback binder
    - Pions paper (report on experiment done at the Brookhaven National Laboratory), ca. 1955; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_15 (Box B-3.3, Folder 15)
    - Parity (colloquium talk), ca. 1955; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_17 (Box B-3.3, Folder 17)
    - Contract No. AT (11-1)-363: contract between the University of Michigan and the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1955; GlaserDA_03_02_02B_02 (Box B-3.2, Folder 2)
    - Optical gaging correspondence, 1955-1958; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_13 (Box B-3.3, Folder 13)
    - Optical gaging correspondence, 1955-1958; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_14 (Box B-3.3, Folder 14)
    - Bevatron Experimental Facilities (UC Berkeley Radiation Lab) blueprints, 1956; GlaserDA_03_02_01B_04oversize (Box B-3.1, Folder 4oversize)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_01 (Box B-3.3, Folder 1)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_02 (Box B-3.3, Folder 2)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_03 (Box B-3.3, Folder 3)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_04 (Box B-3.3, Folder 4)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_05 (Box B-3.3, Folder 5)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_01oversize (Box B-3.3, Folder 1oversize)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_02oversize (Box B-3.3, Folder 2oversize)
    - Kinematics, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_02_03B_03oversize (Box B-3.3, Folder 3oversize)
    - K+ experiment notebook, 1958-1960; GlaserDA_03_02_01C_03 (Box C-3.1, Folder 3)
      Bevatron experiments at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory while visiting professor at UC Berkeley
  - Subseries 3 Student dissertations, 1953-1960
    - Brown, John L., Associated production of strange particles by negative pi mesons, 1958 (Box C-3.1, Folder 4)
      Available online https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/handle/2027.42/3856
    - Bryant, Howard C., The neutral decay mode of the lambda hyperon as observed in a xenon bubble chamber, 1960 (Box C-3.1, Folder 5)
      Available online https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/handle/2027.42/3926
    - Burnstein, Raphael A., The production and interaction of strange particles produced by 1.0 - 1.1 BEV negative pi mesons in a xenon bubble chamber, 1960; GlaserDA_03_03_02C_01 (Box C-3.2, Folder 1)
    - Hartung, Richard W., A study of neutral k(1) meson decays in the xenon bubble chamber, 1960; GlaserDA_03_03_02C_02 (Box C-3.2, Folder 2)
    - Hollyer, Robert N., A study of attentuation in the shock tube, 1953; GlaserDA_03_03_02C_03 (Box C-3.2, Folder 3)
    - Roellig, Leonard O., Elastic scattering of 1.1 positive pions by protons and the elastic scattering of 582 MEV protons by protons, 1959 (Box C-3.2, Folder 4)
      Available online https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/handle/2027.42/7302
    - van Putten, James Dyke, Jr., Determination of the neutral lambda-hyperon decay parameter, alpha, 1960; GlaserDA_03_03_02C_05 (Box C-3.2, Folder 5)
    - Vander Velde, John C., Observation of the associated production of strange particles produced by pi mesons, 1957 (Box C-3.2, Folder 6)
      Available online https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/handle/2027.42/8081
    - Zipf, Theodore F., Study of positive tau meson decays in a propane bubble chamber, 1956 (Box C-3.2, Folder 7)
      Available online https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/handle/2027.42/8508
  - Subseries 4 Teaching, 1949-1959
    - Courses--Physics 26, 1949-1950; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_08 (Box B-3.2, Folder 8)
    - Courses--Physics 45, 1949-1951; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_10 (Box B-3.2, Folder 10)
    - Courses--Physics 45, 1949-1951; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_11 (Box B-3.2, Folder 11)
    - Courses--Physics 46, 1949-1951; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_12 (Box B-3.2, Folder 12)
    - Courses--Physics 25, 1949-1953; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_07 (Box B-3.2, Folder 7)
    - Courses--Physics 52, 1950-1953; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_13 (Box B-3.2, Folder 13)
    - Courses--Physics 224 (Cosmic Rays), 1951-1953; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_14 (Box B-3.2, Folder 14)
    - Courses--Physics 224 (Cosmic Rays), 1951-1953; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_15 (Box B-3.2, Folder 15)
    - Courses--Physics 38, 1952-1953; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_09 (Box B-3.2, Folder 9)
    - Lecture notes, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_04_03B_07 (Box B-3.3, Folder 7)
    - Continental Classroom, 1958-1959; GlaserDA_03_04_02B_01 (Box B-3.2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 5 Miscellaneous, 1955-1959
    - Patents--Security, 1955-1956; GlaserDA_03_05_03B_18 (Box B-3.3, Folder 18)
    - Brussels Worlds Fair, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_05_01B_03 (Box B-3.1, Folder 3)
    - Requests for publications, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_03_05_04B_13 (Box B-3.4, Folder 13)
    - Research Club, 1958; GlaserDA_03_05_04B_12 (Box B-3.4, Folder 12)
- Series 4 University of California at Berkeley, 1958-2006; 4
  - Subseries 1 Administrative material, 1958-2006
    - UC Berkeley employment and salary correspondence, 1958-1966; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_01 (Box C-4.1, Folder 1)
    - Biographical and administrative material I, 1959-1986; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_02 (Box C-4.1, Folder 2)
    - Biographical and administrative material II, 1988-1996; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_03 (Box C-4.1, Folder 3)
    - Biographical and administrative material III, 1996-2003; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_04 (Box C-4.1, Folder 4)
    - Mario Savio court case, UC Berkeley faculty request for dismissal, 1965 January; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_05 (Box C-4.1, Folder 5)
    - Automatic Scanning System (University of California) blueprints and diagrams, 1965; GlaserDA_04_01_05B_04oversize (Box B-4.5, Folder 4oversize)
    - Course material, 1970-1989; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_06 (Box C-4.1, Folder 6)
    - Diving Control Board (UC Berkeley), 1977-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_07 (Box B-4.12, Folder 7)
    - Diving Control Board (UC Berkeley), 1977-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_08 (Box B-4.12, Folder 8)
    - Diving Control Board (UC Berkeley), 1977-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_09 (Box B-4.12, Folder 9)
    - Virus Laboratory annual reports, 1980; 1997; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_07 (Box C-4.1, Folder 7)
    - Chancellor's Office, 1980-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_11B_07 (Box B-4.11, Folder 7)
    - Professional Development Program, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_30 (Box B-4.13, Folder 30)
    - Facilities, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_15 (Box B-4.12, Folder 15)
    - Funding, Research, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_21 (Box B-4.12, Folder 21)
    - Bela Julesz, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_04 (Box B-4.13, Folder 4)
    - Computer--PPDIO, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_11B_10 (Box B-4.11, Folder 10)
    - Computer--PPDIO, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_11B_11 (Box B-4.11, Folder 11)
    - Consulting and patent regulations (conflict of interest), 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_11B_13 (Box B-4.11, Folder 13)
    - Physics Department, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_28 (Box B-4.13, Folder 28)
    - Physics Department, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_29 (Box B-4.13, Folder 29)
    - Library, 1981-1984; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_08 (Box B-4.13, Folder 8)
    - Biological Sciences Building (planning), 1982; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_42 (Box B-4.10, Folder 42)
    - Biophysics, 1982-1983; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_45 (Box B-4.10, Folder 45)
    - Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory, 1983-1985; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_06 (Box B-4.13, Folder 6)
    - Biological Sciences reorganization, 1985; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_43 (Box B-4.10, Folder 43)
    - Affinity Group in Biochemistry, Molecular Biology, Bacteriology, 1985-1986; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_37 (Box B-4.10, Folder 37)
    - Affinity Group in Theoretical Neurobiology, 1986; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_39 (Box B-4.10, Folder 39)
    - Typewriter, 1986-1987; GlaserDA_04_01_14B_01 (Box B-4.14, Folder 1)
    - Sponsor's Project Office, 1986-1989; GlaserDA_04_01_13B_36 (Box B-4.13, Folder 36)
    - Affinity Group in Biophysics, 1986-1992; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_38 (Box B-4.10, Folder 38)
    - Administrative memos and office procedures, 1987-1992; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_35 (Box B-4.10, Folder 35)
    - Administrative memos and office procedures, 1987-1992; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_36 (Box B-4.10, Folder 36)
    - Development Office, UC Berkeley, 1988-1989; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_06 (Box B-4.12, Folder 6)
    - Academic Senate, 1988-1995; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_33 (Box B-4.10, Folder 33)
    - Academic Senate, 1988-1995; GlaserDA_04_01_10B_34 (Box B-4.10, Folder 34)
    - Grant to improve instruction, 1989; GlaserDA_04_01_12B_23 (Box B-4.12, Folder 23)
    - Chancellor's memos, 1989-1990; GlaserDA_04_01_14B_16 (Box B-4.14, Folder 16)
    - Faculty memos, 1989-1995; GlaserDA_04_01_14B_28 (Box B-4.14, Folder 28)
    - Electron Microscope Laboratory and Lawrence Berkeley Lab, 1990-1991; GlaserDA_04_01_14B_24 (Box B-4.14, Folder 24)
    - Copyright information, 1991; GlaserDA_04_01_17B_10 (Box B-4.17, Folder 10)
    - Edwin McMillan, 1991-1992; GlaserDA_04_01_15B_05 (Box B-4.15, Folder 5)
    - UGIS 192, 1992-1993; GlaserDA_04_01_16B_09 (Box B-4.16, Folder 9)
    - Administration, 1993; GlaserDA_04_01_14B_11 (Box B-4.14, Folder 11)
    - Molecular Biology: undergraduate forms, 1993; GlaserDA_04_01_15B_10 (Box B-4.15, Folder 10)
    - Physics at Berkeley, 1997; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_08 (Box C-4.1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence from American Institute of Physics to UC Berkeley Bancroft Library, 2006 July 21; GlaserDA_04_01_01C_09 (Box C-4.1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2 Student dissertations, 1971-1996
    - Beutter, Brent R., Human motion perception in noisy environments, 1993; GlaserDA_04_02_01C_10 (Box C-4.1, Folder 10)
    - Chaudhuri, Avijit, Aspects of metastable apparent motion, 1987; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_01 (Box C-4.2, Folder 1)
      Author inscribed
    - Cruz-Moreno, Jose M., VLSI implementation of cellular neural networks [corrected version], 1996; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_02 (Box C-4.2, Folder 2)
    - Cruz-Moreno, Jose M., VLSI implementation of cellular neural networks [final version], 1996; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_03 (Box C-4.2, Folder 3)
      Author inscribed; includes letter
    - Hanson, James Edwin, Computational mechanics of cellular automata, 1993; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_04 (Box C-4.2, Folder 4)
    - Kung, Fang-chien, Some events in the cell cycle of Escherichia coli, 1976; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_05 (Box C-4.2, Folder 5)
    - Limede de Oliveira, Arlindo Manuel, Inductive learning by selection of minimal complexity representations, 1994; GlaserDA_04_02_02C_06 (Box C-4.2, Folder 6)
    - Lundquist, Dorothy Olive Lola, Attachment of DNA to membrane in Escherichia coli, 1971; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_01 (Box C-4.3, Folder 1)
      Printing error on page 7 - some words unclear
    - Murthy, Praveen K., Scheduling techniques for synchronous and multidimensional synchronous dataflow, 1996 (Box C-4.3, Folder 2)
      Available online http://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/Pubs/TechRpts/1996/ERL-96-79.pdf
    - Neveu, Charles Frederick, Ocular accomodation and the virtual lens, 1995; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_03 (Box C-4.3, Folder 3)
    - Noss, Roger Stephen, The visual processing of curvature in the human observer, 1992; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_04 (Box C-4.3, Folder 4)
    - Ruderman, Daniel Lee, Natural ensembles and sensory signal processing, 1993; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_05 (Box C-4.3, Folder 5)
    - Waskell, Lucy Ann, The isolation and partial characterization of mutants of E. coli with cold sensitive synthesis of DNA, 1973; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_06 (Box C-4.3, Folder 6)
    - Zhou, Peng, Analysis of fractal textures by humans and computers using statistical methods, 1994; GlaserDA_04_02_03C_07 (Box C-4.3, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3 Teaching - Course material, 1981-1994
    - Courses: Molecular Biology 10, 1981; GlaserDA_04_03_12B_02 (Box B-4.12, Folder 2)
    - Courses: Molecular Biology 10, 1981; GlaserDA_04_03_12B_03 (Box B-4.12, Folder 3)
    - Courses: miscellaneous, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_04_03_12B_04 (Box B-4.12, Folder 4)
    - Courses: Physics 250, 1983-1985; GlaserDA_04_03_12B_01 (Box B-4.12, Folder 1)
    - Physics 250: Survey of Neural Networks with Applications to Vision and Other Problems, 1993-1994; GlaserDA_04_03_15B_24 (Box B-4.15, Folder 24)
    - Physics 250: Survey of Neural Networks with Applications to Vision and Other Problems, 1993-1994; GlaserDA_04_03_15B_25 (Box B-4.15, Folder 25)
    - Physics 250: Survey of Neural Networks with Applications to Vision and Other Problems, 1993-1994; GlaserDA_04_03_15B_26 (Box B-4.15, Folder 26)
    - Physics 250: Survey of Neural Networks with Applications to Vision and Other Problems, 1993-1994; GlaserDA_04_03_15B_27 (Box B-4.15, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 4 Miscellaneous, 1960-1994
    - Berkeley Conference on Strong Interactions, 1960; GlaserDA_04_04_05B_11 (Box B-4.5, Folder 11)
    - Berkeley Instrumentation Conference, 1960; GlaserDA_04_04_05B_12 (Box B-4.5, Folder 12)
    - Institute of International Studies: Meeting of War/Peace Research Development Seminar, 1963; GlaserDA_04_04_06B_6a (Box B-4.6, Folder 6a)
    - Books and other publications, orders and information, 1981-1984; GlaserDA_04_04_10B_48 (Box B-4.10, Folder 48)
    - Books and other publications, orders and information, 1981-1984; GlaserDA_04_04_10B_49 (Box B-4.10, Folder 49)
    - Books and other publications, orders and information, 1981-1984; GlaserDA_04_04_11B_01 (Box B-4.11, Folder 1)
    - Evolution versus special creation, 1986; GlaserDA_04_04_12B_11 (Box B-4.12, Folder 11)
    - Risk-taking, 1986; GlaserDA_04_04_13B_32 (Box B-4.13, Folder 32)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research, 1993-1994; GlaserDA_04_04_14B_12 (Box B-4.14, Folder 12)
    - Publications: reprint materials, undated; GlaserDA_04_04_15B_32 (Box B-4.15, Folder 32)
- Series 5 Bubble Chamber (Ann Arbor), 1942-1994; 5
  Includes work done prior to and leading up to the Bubble Chamber
  - Subseries 1 Notebooks, ca. 1949-1959; 1991
    This subseries consists of notebooks with research spanning before and after the invention of the bubble chamber.
    - Notebook I - Mesotron Spectrum, ca. 1949-1950; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_01 (Box C-5.1, Folder 1)
    - Notebook II - Mesotron Spectrum, ca. 1949-1950; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_02 (Box C-5.1, Folder 2)
      Includes loose page notes
    - Notebook III, ca. 1949-1950; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_03 (Box C-5.1, Folder 3)
    - Notebook IV, 1951 November; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_04 (Box C-5.1, Folder 4)
    - Notebook V - Xenon Bubble Chamber, ca. 1952-1957; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_05 (Box C-5.1, Folder 5)
    - Notebook VI - High Energy Physics Colloquium, ca. 1952-1957; 1991; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_06 (Box C-5.1, Folder 6)
      Includes letter regarding date of invention
    - Notebook VII - Field Theory, ca. 1952-1957; GlaserDA_05_01_01C_07 (Box C-5.1, Folder 7)
    - Notebook VIII, 1950 May - 1953 November; GlaserDA_05_01_02C_01 (Box C-5.2, Folder 1)
    - Notebook IX, 1952; GlaserDA_05_01_02C_02 (Box C-5.2, Folder 2)
    - Notebook X, 1952 July - 1953 July; GlaserDA_05_01_02C_03 (Box C-5.2, Folder 3)
      Includes loose page typed notes
    - Notebook XI, 1954 March - November; GlaserDA_05_01_02C_04 (Box C-5.2, Folder 4)
    - Notebook XII, 1954 October - 1955 August; GlaserDA_05_01_02C_05 (Box C-5.2, Folder 5)
      Includes loose page notes dated 1955
    - Notebook XIII, 1955 February - December; GlaserDA_05_01_03C_01 (Box C-5.3, Folder 1)
    - Notebook XIV, 1955 June - July; GlaserDA_05_01_03C_02 (Box C-5.3, Folder 2)
    - Notebook XV - Dispersion Theory - Case, 1956 February - 1959 April; GlaserDA_05_01_03C_03 (Box C-5.3, Folder 3)
      Case in title refers to Kenneth M. Case
    - Notebook XVI, 1956 August - 1957 March; GlaserDA_05_01_03C_04 (Box C-5.3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2 Projects and technical papers, ca. 1951-1968
    - Reference notecards I, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_01 (Box C-5.4, Folder 1)
    - Reference notecards II, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_02 (Box C-5.4, Folder 2)
    - Reference notecards III, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_03 (Box C-5.4, Folder 3)
    - Reference notecards IV, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_04 (Box C-5.4, Folder 4)
    - Reference notecards V, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_05 (Box C-5.4, Folder 5)
    - Orbiting Bubble Chamber, undated; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_06 (Box C-5.4, Folder 6)
    - Bubble Chamber notes and drawings I, ca. 1951-1953; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_07 (Box C-5.4, Folder 7)
    - Project 2281, 1954-1956; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_05 (Box B-5.4, Folder 5)
    - Bubble Chamber reports (Berkeley Hydrogen Bubble Chamber), 1955; GlaserDA_05_02_01B_06 (Box B-5.1, Folder 6)
    - Bubble Chamber reports (Berkeley Hydrogen Bubble Chamber), 1955; GlaserDA_05_02_01B_07 (Box B-5.1, Folder 7)
    - Bubble Chamber notes and drawings II, ca. 1955-1957; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_08 (Box C-5.4, Folder 8)
    - Project administration, 1955-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_01 (Box B-5.4, Folder 1)
    - Project administration, 1955-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_02 (Box B-5.4, Folder 2)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1957-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_01B_02 (Box B-5.1, Folder 2)
    - Progress reports on Contract AT (11-1)363, 1956-1957; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_06 (Box B-5.4, Folder 6)
    - Proposals--Contracts, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_07 (Box B-5.4, Folder 7)
    - Proposals--Contracts, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_08 (Box B-5.4, Folder 8)
    - Proposals--Contracts, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_09 (Box B-5.4, Folder 9)
    - Proposals--Contracts, 1956-1959; GlaserDA_05_02_04B_10 (Box B-5.4, Folder 10)
    - Research notes on the Electro-Scintillation Chamber, 1957 July 19 - August 31; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_09 (Box C-5.4, Folder 9)
    - Methods of particle detection for high energy physics experiments (Glaser and Bradner), ca. 1957; GlaserDA_05_02_03B_8a (Box B-5.3, Folder 8a)
    - Bubble Chamber technology, 1959; GlaserDA_05_02_01B_05 (Box B-5.1, Folder 5)
    - Bubble Chambers and Elementary Particles in the Early Days - Lecture notes, 1968 November 28; GlaserDA_05_02_04C_10 (Box C-5.4, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3 Publications, 1942-1994
    - Publications by others, 1942-1993; GlaserDA_05_03_05C_01; Photocopies, reprints, drafts (Box C-5.5, Folder 1)
    - Scientific American (manuscript of article on Bubble Chamber), 1955; GlaserDA_05_03_05B_01 (Box B-5.5, Folder 1)
    - CERN (European Organization of Nuclear Research), 1956-1955; GlaserDA_05_03_01B_09 (Box B-5.1, Folder 9)
      1956 materials consist mainly of symposium papers by others; 1958 and 1959 materials also include some correspondence
    - CERN (European Organization of Nuclear Research), 1956-1956; GlaserDA_05_03_01B_10 (Box B-5.1, Folder 10)
      1957 materials consist mainly of symposium papers by others; 1958 and 1959 materials also include some correspondence
    - CERN (European Organization of Nuclear Research), 1956-1957; GlaserDA_05_03_01B_11 (Box B-5.1, Folder 11)